Guide to the Julian and Juliette Huxley papers, 1899-1988 MS 512
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series III: Photos & Negatives, 1899-1984, 242565
  - Subseries B: Loose Photographs, 242625
    - Sub-Subseries 5: Places (or Travel), ca. 1932-1984, 242636
      - Africa (Negatives), 242787 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Africa (Slides), 242786 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Artwork, 242785 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Crete, 242784 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Crete (Negatives), 242783 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - France, 242782 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Goat Island, 1975, 242781 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Goat Island, 1975 (Negatives), 242780 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - India, 242779 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Isle of Wight, 242778 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - Isle of Wight (Negatives), 242777 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Israel, 242776 (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - Italy, 242775 (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - Lebanon, 242774 (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - Misc. Negatives, 242773 (Box 20, Folder 19)
      - Sailing, 242772 (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - Sailing (Negatives), 242771 (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - Spain, 242770 (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - Sweden, 242769 (Box 20, Folder 23)
      - Switzerland (Duplicates), 242768 (Box 20, Folder 24)
      - Texas, 1984, 242767 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Texas, 1984 (Negatives), 242766 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Tunisia, 242765 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Unknown, 242764 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Unknown (Probably Africa), 242763 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - USA, Slides, 242762 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - West Africa, Elliot Commission, 1944, 242761 (Box 21, Folder 7-9)
      - Yugoslavia, 242760 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Africa, 242759 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Ghana & Nigeria, 242758 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Gold Coast, Ashanti, 1944, 242757 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Major Thomas /Art Smith, 242756 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Nigeria, 1961, 242755 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - S.E. Nigeria, 1944, 242754 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Sierra Leone, Dakar, Rabat – Elliot Commission, 1944, 242753 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - West Africa, 242752 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - West Africa, 1944, 242751 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - West Africa, Elliot Commission, 1944, 242750 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Africa, 242749 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Africa, 1929, 242748 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Africa, 1929, Negatives, 242747 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Africa, 1960, 242746 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Africa, 1965, 242745 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Africa, Negatives, 242744 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Artwork, 242743 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Australia, 242742 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Australia, Negatives, 242741 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Australia, Slides, 242740 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - California, 242739 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - California, Negatives, 242738 (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - Cambodia, 242737 (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Cambodia, Negatives, 242736 (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - Fiji, 242735 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Indonesia, 242734 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Indonesia, negatives, 242733 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Misc. Negatives, 242732 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Nigeria, 1961, 242731 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Stonehenge, 242730 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Thailand, 242729 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Thailand, Negatives, 242728 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Unknown, 242727 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Whipsnade, 1954, 242726 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Zimbabwe, 242725 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Zimbabwe, negatives, 242724 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - Zimbabwe, slides, 242723 (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - India, 242722 (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
      - India, Negatives & Slides, 242721 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Indonesia/Philippines, 242720 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Indonesia, Negatives, 242719 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Iraq, 242718 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Iraq, Negatives, 242717 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Jordan, 242716 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Mexico, 242715 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Mexico, Negatives, 242714 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Africa, 242713 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Africa, slides, 242712 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Ethiopia, 1963, 242711 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Ethiopia, Negatives, 242710 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Fiji, 242709 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Israel, 242708 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Misc. Negatives, 242707 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Philippines, 242706 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - Philippines, Negatives, 242705 (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - Spain, 1957 (Coto Donana, Granada, Madrid), 242704 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - Spain, 1957, Negatives, 242703 (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - Spain, 1957, Slides, 242702 (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - Thailand, 242701 (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - Tunisia, Slides, 242700 (Box 26, Folder 14)
      - Turkey, 1970, 242699 (Box 26, Folder 15)
      - Turkey, 1970, Negatives, 242698 (Box 26, Folder 16)
      - Africa, 242697 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Africa, 1971, 242696 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Anatomy, 242695 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Artwork, 242694 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Australia, 242693 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Best, Alan, 242692 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - British Virgin Islands, 1982, 242691 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Budapest, 242690 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Budapest, c. 1945, 242689 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - California, 242688 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Casablanca, 242687 (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - Chile, 242686 (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - Colombia, 242685 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - Croatia, 1969, 242684 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - Croatia, 1969, Negatives, 242683 (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - Ecuador, 242682 (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - Egypt, 242681 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - France, 242680 (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - France, 1948, 242679 (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - Goat Island, 242678 (Box 27, Folder 20)
      - Greece, 242677 (Box 27, Folder 21)
      - Haiti, 242676 (Box 27, Folder 22)
      - Houses, 242675 (Box 27, Folder 23)
      - Huxley, Zoe, 242674 (Box 27, Folder 24)
      - Huxley Family (various members), 242673 (Box 27, Folder 25)
      - India, 242672 (Box 27, Folder 26)
      - India, Negatives, 242671 (Box 27, Folder 27)
      - Indonesia, 242670 (Box 27, Folder 28)
      - Isle of Wight, 242669 (Box 27, Folder 29)
      - Italy, 242668 (Box 27, Folder 30)
      - Italy, 1918 (soldiers in uniform), 242667 (Box 27, Folder 31)
      - Italy, Negatives, 242666 (Box 27, Folder 32)
      - Malta, 1974, 242665 (Box 27, Folder 33)
      - Mexico, 242664 (Box 27, Folder 34)
      - MJH's Garden, 242663 (Box 27, Folder 35)
      - Misc. Negatives, 242662 (Box 27, Folder 36)
      - Misc. Slides, 242661 (Box 27, Folder 37)
      - Moore, Henry, 242660 (Box 27, Folder 38)
      - Notes, 242659 (Box 27, Folder 39)
      - "Our Lab" – Rice U., 242658 (Box 27, Folder 40)
      - People, Unknown, 242657 (Box 27, Folder 41)
      - Peru, 242656 (Box 27, Folder 42)
      - Rice University, 242655 (Box 27, Folder 43)
      - Rice University, Negatives, 242654 (Box 27, Folder 44)
      - Scientific, 242653 (Box 27, Folder 45)
      - Scotland, 242652 (Box 27, Folder 46)
      - Spain, 242651 (Box 27, Folder 47)
      - Sweden, 242650 (Box 27, Folder 48)
      - Switzerland, 242649 (Box 27, Folder 49)
      - Switzerland, 1964 (?), 242648 (Box 27, Folder 50)
      - Switzerland, 1971, 242647 (Box 27, Folder 50)
      - Switzerland, 1971, 242646 (Box 27, Folder 51)
      - Syria, 242645 (Box 27, Folder 52)
      - Thailand, 242644 (Box 27, Folder 53)
      - Travel, Unknown, 242643 (Box 27, Folder 54)
      - Turkey, 242642 (Box 27, Folder 55)
      - USA?, 242641 (Box 27, Folder 56)
      - USA, 1965, Negatives, 242640 (Box 27, Folder 57)
      - USA, Negatives?, 242639 (Box 27, Folder 58)
      - Vienna, 242638 (Box 27, Folder 59)
      - Yugoslavia, 242637 (Box 27, Folder 60)
    - Sub-Subseries 6: Wildlife, 242630
      Note that there are many photographs of wildlife in the Travel Sub-subseries, particularly among the photographs made in Africa and Israel.]
      - Wildlife, Misc. Slides, 242635 (Box 27, Folder 61)
      - Wildlife, Negatives, 242634 (Box 27, Folder 62)
      - Wildlife, Whipsnade, 242633 (Box 27, Folder 63)
      - Wildlife, Whipsnade, Negatives, 242632 (Box 27, Folder 64)
      - Flat Box – Birds, Animals, Shellfish, Insects (There are many 8x10, 5x7, and smaller photographs in this box. ), 242631 (Box 28, Folder -)
    - Sub-Subseries 7: Oversized, 242626
      - Arnold/Baillot/Huxley Family; Structures; Landscapes; Drawings, 242629 (Box 29, Folder -)
      - JSH only (Includes a couple of caricatures and one drawing), 242628 (Box 30, Folder -)
      - Album – Africa, 1929 (Many are loose. The photographs depict African landscapes, people, wildlife, and flora. Very few are of MJH or JSH, 242627 (Box 31, Folder -)
  - Subseries C: Negatives, 242566
    - Australia, 242624 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Cambodia, 242623 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - England, 242622 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Egypt, 242621 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Fiji, 242620 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - France, 242619 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Greece, 242618 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Guatemala, 242617 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Indonesia, 242616 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Iran, 242615 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Lebanon, 242614 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Mexico, 242613 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Moore, Henry, 242612 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Poland, 242611 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Syria, 242610 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Unknown, 242609 (Box 32, Folder 16-17)
    - Notebook – "Index to Colour Negatives", 242608 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Unknown, 242607 (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
    - Whipsnade, 242606 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Yugoslavia, 242605 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Africa, 242604 (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
    - Boys, 242603 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Cambodia, 242602 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Danube, 242601 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - England, 242600 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - England, Negatives, 242599 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - England, Slides, 242598 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - France, 242597 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Friends, 242596 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Germany, 242595 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Haiti, Slide, 242594 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Huxley Family, 242593 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - India, 242592 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Iran, 242591 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Iraq, 242590 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Ireland, 242589 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Isle of Wight, 242588 (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Israel, 242587 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Istanbul, 242586 (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Italy, 242585 (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - Mexico, 242584 (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - Oxford, 242583 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Oxford, Negatives, 242582 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Portugal, 242581 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Scotland, 242580 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Spain, 242579 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Stonehenge, 242578 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Switzerland, 242577 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Switzerland, Negatives, 242576 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Syria, 242575 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Thailand, 242574 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Tunisia, 242573 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Unknown, 242572 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - USA, 242571 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Wales, 242570 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Wales, Slides, 242569 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Whipsnade, 242568 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Wildlife, 242567 (Box 35, Folder 16)
- Series IV: Audio Tapes & Films, n.d., 242563
  - Three films, five audio tapes, 1 cassette, 242564 (Box 36, Folder -)
- Series V: Correspondence, 1917-1945, 242548
  - Business, 242562 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Family, 242561 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Friends, 242560 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - JSH, MJH Corresp., 242559 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - JSH to MJH, 1936, 242558 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - J's Fugue, 1930-32, 242557 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - JSH Letters under Stress, 242556 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Juliette Huxley to May Sarton, 242555 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Juliette/Julian Huxley during Recovery from Breakdown, 1945, 242554 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Juliette Huxley/Kot, 242553 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Kathleen Fordham (JSH's girlfriend 1917-18), 242552 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - MJH to JSH, 1932, 242551 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Viola Ilma/Julian Huxley, 242550 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - One tied bundle of correspondence copies (The letters appear to all be to/from JSH & MJH. The dates vary but are not in chronological order.), 242549 (Box 38, Folder -)
- Series VI: Awards & Honors, 242546
  - Awards and honors, 242547 (Box 39-40, Folder -)
- Series VII: Clippings, Printed Material, & JSH Memorabilia, 242541
  - Huxley Vital Records, 242545 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - JSH Memorabilia, 242544 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings, 242543 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Printed Ephemera (about Huxleys & Friends), 242542 (Box 41, Folder 4)